August, Wednesday
August, Thursday
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
Saionji-sensei...
You should go and get some sleep.
I'm fine.
Besides, if I sleep now, we'll never make the deadline.
Why...
...don't we go outside for some fresh air?
We're taking a break.
Okay.
See you later.
You guys should get some rest if you need it, too.
If anything happens, call my cell phone.
We'll be pretty much fine for tonight.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's so hot...
Your hand feels like ice.
You shouldn't keep your room so cold.
But if I turn off the air conditioning, you guys sweat all over the manuscripts.
I've heard that stress can cause your body temperature to fall, too...
Huh...
Anyway, about that new job you were mentioning recently...
I don't think it's worth taking if it'll cause a drop in the quality of your current work.
You've never been very strong, physically or mentally, Maa-chan.
And you're just now making enough to put food on your plate.
So I don't think there's any need to get greedy with money.
But...
What?
The public's current interest in my work could easily disappear come next year.
There's always a new generation of artists hitting the scene...
And people can grow bored with your work just like that...
You're way too pessimistic, Maa-chan.
It's not good for you.
You have ink on your face again.
Oh, yeah?
Geez...
You're a girl, so you should really-
I'm not a girl!
I'm a manga artist!
I'm going home to work!
I'm sorry to bother you all...
Geez...
I can't be bothered to go to work...
Good morning...
Why didn't you come out when I called you?
Sorry. It's too hot...
Does that cool you down?
Yeah.
Shall we make your lunch?
Yeah!
Hey, give me a hand!
Okay!
Rin's summer holidays have started.
We make her lunch together in the morning,
and then she goes to a daycare centre.
Do you want to visit Granddad's grave next Saturday?
It's almost time for the Bon Festival,
after all, and your flowers should be...
TL Note: A Japanese holiday when it is customary to honour the deceased spirits of your ancestors.
Huh?
What's wrong? You don't want to go?
The bellflowers haven't bloomed yet, so...
Ah, right. I guess they'll take a little longer.
Then how about we buy some from a florist this time? We'll take yours once they've bloomed.
Okay...
It's true that Granddad would be happy if you brought him bellflowers that you grew.
Right?
But just having you there would make him the happiest.
That's the most important thing.
Right...
I see.
If Rin weren't here, I doubt I'd be thinking of Granddad like this...
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Ah, Kouki-kun!
Hey! You'll mess it all up if you move!
My bad...
Why is your hair so fine, anyway?
I don't know!
What?
Wait a second!
Hey, we're going to be late!
What's with him?
Daikichi, how many more days?
Obon Festival
About ten, I guess.
Found one!
A cicada shell!
A shell?
Man, this is nostalgic...
I've got a ton of them in here...
That's disgusting!
Stop shaking them!
We're going to be late!
Hey!
Look out for cars!
I've been here lots of times.
With Granddad?
Yeah.
Really? I guess Granny's grave is here too, huh?
Granddad's granny?
No, mine.
Granny and Granddad had a child, my mum.
And then, she had me.
Ah! So your mum is Granddad's daughter!
But...
That means I'm your mother's sister.
Crap! I shouldn't have pointed her in that direction!
This way!
It's here!
Kaga Family Grave
It's all wet...
That vase...
Masako-san had one just like it.
Ma...
What the hell? But she didn't even come to the funeral...
Rin, I'll be right back.
Huh?
Wait here for a bit.
Pull out some of the weeds.
Okay!
What should I do?
Who goes to visit a grave with a guy, anyway?
W-Woof!
What is it?! What are you doing here?!
I thought you were some sort of stalker...
We happened to come to the graveyard after you.
It was really just a coincidence.
But I thought I should let you know...
...that Rin's here with me.
She's at Granddad's grave.
Um... I...
Rin's very dear to me,
so I don't really think very fondly of you,
and I don't really care about what's going on in your life.
I have no intention of forcing the two of you to meet again, unless she wants it.
I know that!
What did you want to tell me so badly that you chased after me?
I wanted to ask if you wanted to at least secretly get a look at her.
We're going to clean the grave, light some incense and go home,
so we'll probably be around for a while.
Anyway, Rin's waiting for me. I have to go.
It's up to you.
We'll just be doing what we came here to do.
Rin... Sorry...
Were you waiting long?
Um...
Are you okay?
Um... I had something to...
Eh?
No, sorry.
Were you waiting long?
Not too long.
Were you lonely?
You're being weird!
What are you getting so worked up for?
I'm not being weird...
Take this.
Okay.
Plant them there.
Right!
She's not a baby any more...
Blood ties are amazing...
I know. She looks just like you, Maa-chan.
That back...
She's pretty cute.
That sense of distance...
It's so much like Souichi-san...
I'm so glad...
That was really a shock.
I guess coincidences like this only pop up when it's almost Obon, huh?
She turns seven today.
I see.
Learning about your daughter was a shock, too,
but I thought maybe the guy was your ex-boyfriend.
You've got to be kidding me.
He doesn't have a single brain cell in that head of his.
Though that could change in another half-century.
Half... century?
It's logical to assume that that guy was her boyfriend.
Daikichi? You know...
I guess it's not such a bad thing, but...
Daikichi!
For someone madly in love, it didn't
take her long to find somebody else.
Hey! Daikichi!
Y-Yeah?
Can we go to Granddad's?
It's close by, isn't it?
Hm... But it's not Granddad's house any more.
Is somebody living there?
No, nobody's living there, but...
It belongs to my uncle on my mother's side.
The Buddhist altar is there too, so...
I see...
Fine, I'll ask my uncle if we can at least take a look around the garden.
Really?!
Just the garden!
Right!
I know the way!
I'm going to take them up on that job, after all.
Seriously?!
Will you be okay, Maa-chan?
I gave her up for the sake of my job.
I should be doing it.
You already are!
You're working harder than anyone needs to!
It's not enough...
I need to work so hard that I can't even
remember what I had for dinner the night before.
Oh, come on. Even I forget that.
If I don't do that...
If I don't forget all of those things...
I...
Just a little further!
It's just the same as it used to be, isn't it?
But you've changed so much.
They're gone!
The bellflowers are gone!
The dirt is gone, too...
Those bellflowers were so important to Granddad...
I'm sure he didn't mean to just yank them out.
Even my uncle could tell you Granddad's favourite flower.
But when Winter comes, they wither.
He probably didn't know that they bloom again in Spring.
And these stones...
If you don't spread them around,
the area will become overrun with weeds before you know it.
I'm so glad we got Rin's fragrant olive tree out...
That was lucky.
But luckily, we have bellflowers for Granddad at our house, too!
So we're okay!
Right!
Maybe things changing isn't always a bad thing.
But that grave will always be Granddad's grave, okay?
Yeah!
Rin...
Yeah?
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday, Rin-chan
A chocolate cake!
Saionji-sensei, can you do a final check?
Are you okay?
You really seem like you're pushing yourself too hard this time...
When you say things like that, my hands stop working properly, so stop it.
Go ahead.
I'll finish it, no matter what.
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Daikichi! All of the nighttime stalls are going to close!
No, they won't!
Just like Granddad.
Here's Kouki-kun!
What's wrong?
We were supposed to be meeting at the shrine, right?
Mum's too slow.
You're not wearing a yukata?
I can't jump in one!
Awesome, right?
What about your mum?
She said she'd meet us at the shrine after she put on her yukata.
Let's go! The nighttime stalls will close!
Daikichi, look out for cars!
I know!
Wait! It's hard to run in wooden clogs!
I'll carry you!
No!
You can carry me!